<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reverse on ret2school</title>
    <link>https://ret2school.github.io/tags/reverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reverse on ret2school</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ret2school.github.io/tags/reverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[ESAIP CTF 2023 - reverse] Dothell Revenge</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/dothell_revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/dothell_revenge/</guid>
      <description>Dothell Revenge  Solves : 3
They downed the CTF infra as soon as it ended so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to save the challenge prompt :(
Author: Oogle
 Dothell Revenge was a hard reverse-engineering challenge from ESAIP CTF 2023. It was a modified version of Dothell, a challenge from the 2022 edition that had 0 solves. I didn&amp;rsquo;t participate IRL last year, but I did this year, and even beat two of the best reversers I know to the first blood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Grey Cat CTF Quals 2023 - reverse] crackme1</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/crackme1_greycat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/crackme1_greycat/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: A challenge with obfuscated JavaScript, with some WebGL shaders to reverse.
Description: When the correct key is entered, you will see a nice image.
When we open the webpage, we can first inspect the HTML code.
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;canvas id=&amp;#34;c&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/canvas&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;input-container&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;input id=&amp;#34;textInput&amp;#34; type=&amp;#34;text&amp;#34; placeholder=&amp;#34;Enter Key&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;button id=&amp;#34;submitButton&amp;#34; class=&amp;#34;submit-button&amp;#34;&amp;gt;Submit&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p id=&amp;#34;flag&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://webgl2fundamentals.org/webgl/resources/webgl-utils.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;https://webgl2fundamentals.org/webgl/resources/m4.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;script src=&amp;#34;/app.js&amp;#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; We can first see that there is an empty &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; tag with id flag, which will probably be used to display the flag when the correct key is entered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UTCTF 2023 - reverse] Welcome</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>UTCTF 2023: Welcome  Welcome
1000
Note: while this challenge is nominally RE, there is some crypto-level/crypto-style math involved too.
Welcome to UTCTF! I made a special last minute program just for you to display a wonderful welcome message (+ flag!) I may have accidentally (okay&amp;hellip; purposely) made a small bug in my math &amp;gt; that makes this unsolvable(TM). Can you figure it out and fix it for me please?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Breizh CTF 2022- reverse] Baby</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/baby/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/baby/</guid>
      <description>Value: 50 Description: Le reverse c&#39;est quand même vachement compliqué... ou pas ? Auteur: Worty Format : BZHCTF{}  Like all the CTF challenges named &amp;ldquo;Baby&amp;rdquo;, this challenge was very simple.
You just had to open the source code in radare2 to see the flag in clear:
&amp;gt; r2 baby [0x00001070]&amp;gt; aaa [Cannot find function at 0x00001070 sym. and entry0 (aa) [x] Analyze all flags starting with sym. and entry0 (aa) [x] Analyze function calls (aac) [x] Analyze len bytes of instructions for references (aar) [x] Check for objc references [x] Check for vtables [x] Type matching analysis for all functions (aaft) [x] Propagate noreturn information [x] Use -AA or aaaa to perform additional experimental analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[TRACS 2021 - RE] Coffre</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/safe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/safe/</guid>
      <description>Intro  Epreuve 12-3 – Coffre En tant que stagiaire vous avez accès aux locaux de la NSB. Vous allez collecter des informations dans les locaux. Un coffre est présent dans les locaux en salle rideau. Il appartient à Richard Cresus de la Tune. Essayez d’ouvrir ce coffre. Quel est l’IBAN contenu dans le coffre ? Format de la réponse : IBAN sans séparateur.
 Basically, we have to crack open an electronic safe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[CyberSecurityRumble 2021 - RE / Forensics] The Compromise</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/compromise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/compromise/</guid>
      <description>The Compromise (300 pts)  The SOC team of the BrighSoul QPL (Quantum Physic Labs) is continuously monitoring HTTP proxy and DNS outbound traffic and has identified suspicious DNS traffic to the server authoritative (NS) for the domain thedarkestside.org.
Upon investigation, they presume that an internal windows workstation with has been compromised with a Colbalt Strike beacon running as the executable named ntupdate.exe. The workstation belongs to the R&amp;amp;D team and they are suspicions that files containing critical Intellectual Property information have been exfiltrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[CyberSecurityRumble 2021 - RE / Game Hacking] CSRunner</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/csrunner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/csrunner/</guid>
      <description>Collect green stuff, avoid red guys. Easy as pie, right? Not even your speedhacks will help you here! You might have to take a closer look and inspect it carefully. Have fun &amp;amp; good luck!
 This challenge is a game, according to its description. Since I gave up on the challenge I was trying to do (NOdeBANKing), I went to help other teammates blocked on this challenge.
This game was using Unity3D as engine, where game logic is usually written in C# or other language that compiles to MSIL.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
