<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fofo on ret2school</title>
    <link>https://ret2school.github.io/tags/fofo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fofo on ret2school</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ret2school.github.io/tags/fofo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[CyberSecurityRumble 2021 - RE / Forensics] The Compromise</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/compromise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/compromise/</guid>
      <description>The Compromise (300 pts)  The SOC team of the BrighSoul QPL (Quantum Physic Labs) is continuously monitoring HTTP proxy and DNS outbound traffic and has identified suspicious DNS traffic to the server authoritative (NS) for the domain thedarkestside.org.
Upon investigation, they presume that an internal windows workstation with has been compromised with a Colbalt Strike beacon running as the executable named ntupdate.exe. The workstation belongs to the R&amp;amp;D team and they are suspicions that files containing critical Intellectual Property information have been exfiltrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hitcon CTF 2020 - forensic] AC1750</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/forensic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/forensic/</guid>
      <description>Hello world,
The write up is about the AC1750 challenge in HITCON ctf. It&amp;rsquo;s a forensic challenge, where we need to analyze packets captured by Wireshark to find out what an attacker is doing on the network.
First, we need to analyze intercepted traffic with wireshark. We see a lot of HTTP packets, and some contain &amp;ldquo;Archer&amp;rdquo; references. We can see weird UDP packets with port 20002.
After some google-fu on port 20002, we come accross this, and we can see there is a CVE targeting T-Link Archer devices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
