<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ctf on ret2school</title>
    <link>https://ret2school.github.io/tags/ctf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ctf on ret2school</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ret2school.github.io/tags/ctf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[AeroCTF 2021 - web] Localization is hard</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/localization_is_hard_wu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/localization_is_hard_wu/</guid>
      <description>[Localization is hard - web] AeroCTF 0x00 To solve this challenge we had to exploit a SSTI on Thymeleaf and lead that into a Remote Code Execution
0x01 Discovering the vulnerability The challenge description talk about a Coffee who made for CTFers and in English and in Russian.
Btw , the challenge description tell us that the flag should be located at / on the file system, this maybe mean that we have to get an access to the machine to read the flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[AeroCTF 2021 - RE] BashD00r</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/bashd00r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/bashd00r/</guid>
      <description>Aero CTF 2021 - BashD00r (500 pts) This is the second challenge I was able to solve, and the hardest one. The task is below:
 There seems to be something wrong with our bash.
Can you see if anyone has entered the backdoor?
bash.7z
 So we are given a archive, which contains a &amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo; binary. This binary was backdoored, so we need to find it to get the flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[AeroCTF 2021 - RE] dummyper</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/dummyper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/dummyper/</guid>
      <description>Aero CTF 2021 - Dummyper (454 pts) This the first challenge I did. The challenge&amp;rsquo;s task was:
 This stupid program has encrypted our flag.
We only have a dump left.
 With a mysterious &amp;ldquo;dump.7z&amp;rdquo; that contains a &amp;ldquo;dump&amp;rdquo; file. This file is an ELF binary, so we load it in IDA.
Overview IDA complains about broken section table, but still succeeds to load the bin. We get classical glibc&amp;rsquo;s __libc_start_main, and the &amp;ldquo;main&amp;rdquo; function which looks like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UnionCTF 2021 - web] Cr0wnAir</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/writeup_cr0wnair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/writeup_cr0wnair/</guid>
      <description>The challenge can be found right here.
UnionCTF - Cr0wnAir To solve this challenge, we had to exploit a vulnerability in jpv which allows us to bypass the regex validation in order to get a JWT. Then, we were able to change the algorithm from RS256 to HS256 and forge a new JWT with the public key, a key that we were able to retrieve thanks to a weak e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UnionCTF 2021 - RE] Unionware</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/unionware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/unionware/</guid>
      <description>UnionCTF - Unionware This challenge gives us two files: an &amp;ldquo;unionware.ps1&amp;rdquo; and a &amp;ldquo;important_homework.txt.unionware&amp;rdquo; containing seemingly random bytes. The challenge tells us that a ransomware encrypted the important homework and asks us to decrypt it.
Analyzing the Powershell While looking at the powershell, we can see an obfuscated Powershell command, which seems to split some random string and then evaluating it. So, we&amp;rsquo;ll just run the part of the script which deobfuscates the payload without executing it, which give us:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UnionCTF 2021 - pwn] babyrarf</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/babyrarf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/babyrarf/</guid>
      <description>The binary can be found right here.
[UnionCTF] Babyrarf Welcome guys,
This Write-Up is about de first pwn challenge of unionctf: babyrarf. It was a really easy challenge with a stack based buffer overflow. The source code was provided so, no need to reverse the binary :).
Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the src!
#include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;stdlib.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;stdint.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;unistd.h&amp;gt; typedef struct attack { uint64_t id; uint64_t dmg; } attack; typedef struct character { char name[10]; int health; } character; uint8_t score; int read_int(){ char buf[10]; fgets(buf, 10, stdin); return atoi(buf); } void get_shell(){ execve(&amp;#34;/bin/sh&amp;#34;, NULL, NULL); } attack choose_attack(){ attack a; int id; puts(&amp;#34;Choose an attack:\n&amp;#34;); puts(&amp;#34;1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Hitcon CTF 2020 - forensic] AC1750</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/forensic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/forensic/</guid>
      <description>Hello world,
The write up is about the AC1750 challenge in HITCON ctf. It&amp;rsquo;s a forensic challenge, where we need to analyze packets captured by Wireshark to find out what an attacker is doing on the network.
First, we need to analyze intercepted traffic with wireshark. We see a lot of HTTP packets, and some contain &amp;ldquo;Archer&amp;rdquo; references. We can see weird UDP packets with port 20002.
After some google-fu on port 20002, we come accross this, and we can see there is a CVE targeting T-Link Archer devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[AeroCTF 2020 - RE] go away</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/aero_ctf_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/aero_ctf_2020/</guid>
      <description>Hello world,
This writeup concerns the most difficult challenge I did on the CTF (having occupied myself a few hours to break it). At first glance, we have an &amp;ldquo;obfuscated&amp;rdquo; binary, which makes system calls to mmap and mprotect: we immediately think of a packer, and we will therefore have to unpack it.
Unpacking crackme Unpacking is not a problem on Linux when you are used to malware packers on Windows, thanks to radare2 and its visual mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[AeroCTF 2020 - RE] 1000 and 1 night</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/1000_and_1_night/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/1000_and_1_night/</guid>
      <description>Author: supersnail
Files can be found here
For this challenge, we get an archive with a lot of files, the name of which seems to be a hash. Each file is an ELF x86_64 program file. In addition, a server listens, and requests:
Enter valid token to binary with name &amp;lt;8c235f89a8143a28a1d6067e959dd858&amp;gt; Token: at connection. We therefore understand quickly enough that we will have to automate the reversing of all these ELFs to send the correct token back to the server, and thus have the flag, the server requesting a series of tokens before spitting the flag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[UTCTF 2020 - RE] Crack the heart</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/crack_the_heart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/crack_the_heart/</guid>
      <description>Author: supersnail
For this challenge, I first noticed (like in every other writeups) a big structure of offsets, that pointed to &amp;ldquo;funclets&amp;rdquo; followed by jump with rcx-relative offsets.
The relative jump function:
The first funclet just checks for the process being debugged, the &amp;ldquo;load_r9&amp;rdquo; funclet that jumps to the next funclet after skipping &amp;ldquo;n&amp;rdquo; bytes of garbage. Then the crackme calls a funclet &amp;ldquo;write_message&amp;rdquo; with the parameters (offset to &amp;ldquo;Why should I go out with you?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[CSAW CTF 2020 - RE] Cuba</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/cuba/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/cuba/</guid>
      <description>Hi
This is my write up for the challange Cuba of CSAW CTF 2020 :
So this challenge is a CUBA program wrapped in a Windows Executable. CUBA is a GPU langage created by NVIDIA to work around GPU with high performance langage.
https://docs.nvidia.com/cuda/cuda-c-programming-guide/index.html
Luckily there is a public SDK for it, with a disassembler :
https://docs.nvidia.com/cuda/cuda-binary-utilities/index.html
Using a tool called cuobjdump, we can extract the assembly code :
To extract ptx text from a host binary, use the following command: cuobjdump -ptx &amp;lt;host binary&amp;gt;  And after reversing the output, we can see that it&amp;rsquo;s a simple xor looping through a ciphered flag</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Team introduction</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/list_team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/list_team/</guid>
      <description>Members The team is composed of:
 nasm (17 yo, interested in RE/pwn) supersnail (chad reverser) Zeynn (18 yo, web/steg/cypto) x. (the Guesser, the carry-er) Tek 0xPierre r0da (RE stuff) op (pwn/RE, a little bit of everything :) ) look Ast4te  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
