<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2023 on ret2school</title>
    <link>https://ret2school.github.io/tags/2023/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2023 on ret2school</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ret2school.github.io/tags/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[ESAIP CTF 2023 - crypto] All crypto challenges</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/esaip_crypto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/esaip_crypto/</guid>
      <description>This article contains write-ups for all cryptography challenges from ESAIP CTF 2023. All challenge files, prompts and solves are available here.
The event was nice and I had a great time competing with my friends. However, I&amp;rsquo;d like to quickly rant before diving into the write-ups.
&amp;lt;rant&amp;gt;
 I can&amp;rsquo;t believe this has to be said but before giving source code, please make sure that it works. Added bonus: publish the Dockerfiles you use so players don&amp;rsquo;t have to waste time debugging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[JustCTF - crypto] Vaulted</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/vaulted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/vaulted/</guid>
      <description>Vaulted  This secure multisignature application will keep our flag safe. Mind holding on to one of the backup keys?
nc vaulted.nc.jctf.pro 1337
Author: Tjaden Hess from Trail of Bits
 Vaulted was an easy crypto challenge from JustCTF 2023. To be fair it wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a crypto challenge, you&amp;rsquo;d instantly know how to solve the challenge if you had a bit of crypto knowledge (especially on elliptic curves and how points can be represented) but if you didn&amp;rsquo;t a bit of source code reading would make the solution obvious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[ESAIP CTF 2023 - reverse] Dothell Revenge</title>
      <link>https://ret2school.github.io/post/dothell_revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ret2school.github.io/post/dothell_revenge/</guid>
      <description>Dothell Revenge  Solves: 3
It seems that you now need a password to get some stars&amp;hellip; But you don&amp;rsquo;t have any. Time for some hacking!
Author: Oogle
 Dothell Revenge was a hard reverse-engineering challenge from ESAIP CTF 2023. It was a modified version of Dothell, a challenge from the 2022 edition that had 0 solves. I didn&amp;rsquo;t participate IRL last year, but I did this year, and even beat two of the best reversers I know to the first blood.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
